Hey everyone and thanks for jumping back
into the cryptoverse.
Today we're going to talk about Bitcoin
as we've rallied back up to the bare
market resistance band. If you guys like
the content, make sure you subscribe to
the channel, give the video a thumbs up,
and also check out the sale on Into the
Cryptoverse Premium at into the
cryptoverse.com.
It was a fairly exciting day in the
crypto markets after volatility has been
compressing for a long time and Bitcoin
has now rallied back up to the bare
market resistance band. One of the
things we've talked about probably for
what the last four or five months is
that Bitcoin is essentially being
compressed between the bare market
resistance band and the 200 week moving
average. Okay, so you can see we're kind
of going back and forth between these
two zones. And so the question is is
right like which way is this ultimately
going to break right? Is it going to
break to the upside or is it going to
break to the downside? You know, I've
talked a lot about where I think this is
going to go, how I think it's going to
play out. Um, you know, what normally
happens as we get further out into the
midterm year. And, you know, it's
important again to have a strategy. And
a lot of people have reached out today,
right? And they've said like, well, you
know, Bitcoin's up a lot. Like, what
does that mean? And again, there is this
is a a a sort of a candid reminder that
the strategy that I use for Bitcoin in
midterm years is to DCA it in the second
half of the midterm year, right?
Starting on July 1st. And the reason for
that is because it is so hard to get the
bottom. Now, coincidentally, July 1st
ended up being the low, at least so far.
If you DCA Bitcoin starting in, you
know, the summer of 2018, you would have
caught some nice rallies and then
eventually the market dropped, right? If
you did the same thing in 2018, you
would have caught some nice rallies and
then eventually the market dropped. Um,
so, you know, is it is it possible that
that we don't get that final drop?
It's possible, right? I mean, like
anything's possible and that's why a DCA
strategy works best. It helps to deal
with the FOMO, right? Like the emotions
that can occur when you get rallies,
especially if you're not buying at all.
And that's the reason why it makes sense
in my opinion to do that. The other
thing I'd like to say as well is that if
you are absolutely convinced beyond a
shadow of a doubt, right, if you're
convinced that the low is in and now
you're mad at yourself for not buying,
one of the things to consider is that
Bitcoin is below 70K, right? Like, you
know, from the highs, Bitcoin is still
down almost 50%.
And so there there's a reality of you
don't always even have to time the
bottoms to make money, right? As long as
you get the majority of the trend, it
should work out in your favor. So if
you're convinced that the low is in,
then don't let you know that potentially
dissuade you from or don't let it don't
become mad at yourself, right, for not
for not getting in. you can always
get in, right? Like there there's
there's always going to be more cycles
and that's not ever going to change in
my opinion. Right? Now, obviously some
people think that Bitcoin won't won't
make it long term. I I would disagree
with that, but at the same time, you
know, is there still some evidence that
Bitcoin could go lower? Yeah, like it
could. I mean, and and we've gone
through that. The MVRVZ score, for
example, right? the, you know, the the
realized price. We haven't gone below
that. Now, maybe we don't. Maybe we go
below it in, you know, in the future,
right? Like maybe we just go back up and
and then we go below it in the future
when no one's expecting it. But a lot of
times in midterm years,
Bitcoin gets rallies, right? And and
sometimes we even go above the bare
market resistance band uh before before
heading back down. and and so I think
that you know it's a little premature I
think to necessarily say that it's over
in terms of the bare market especially
considering like if you look at at the
length of time of this bare market and
and like look at it with respect to the
last couple of bare markets it's not
like we never had little rallies right I
mean you can look at at the chart you
see this rally like the rally we just
had by bitcoin that feels like so
amazing and and like you know like what
a crazy rally to you know to to see.
It's this little move on the chart and
we even in last cycle we actually had a
similar move around this time, right?
That was actually even a larger rally
than the one we just had,
right? It was even a bigger rally and
yet it still didn't necessarily dictate
that the low was in, right? We still
eventually went lower. So, I think it's
probably important to have some like
invalidation levels or invalidation
points in time. I I think if Bitcoin's
going to go lower before the next bull
market begins, it'll happen before the
end of the year, frankly, right? Like I
I think it'll happen before the end of
the year. And if it doesn't happen
before the end of the year, I do not
think it makes sense to be a bear going
into 2027. That that would be my
assessment. I I think it it makes sense
to be a bull going into 2027. The only
question is is, you know, is there
another drop between now and then? And,
you know, there's been a couple of times
this year already where we had some
pretty nice rallies and to a lot of
people it felt like the bare market was
over, but it wasn't, right? I mean,
we've had several rallies that were to
levels much higher than where we are
right now and and the bare market was
not in fact over. So for now, I I think
in terms of time, the invalidation for
me would be if we go for the rest of the
year without a lower low, I don't think
it would make sense to call for a lower
low beyond that. But because of where we
are in the cycle, there is still some
evidence to suggest that it it might
happen. And you know, you don't even
have to look that far. are I mean if you
look at 2022 you know Bitcoin had
several rallies even later in the year
than this I mean Bitcoin rallied up from
this low in September which again is
later in the midterm year than we are
now Bitcoin rallied up 23%
and then still fell back down and then
from this low it rallied up
almost 19%
and fell back down right right here this
so you had you know, a couple of 20%
rallies. Now, if you look at the current
rally from the low, we're up about 20 21
22%. So, it's not that we haven't seen
the rallies before, like we have. The
question is is like when when is it
over? When do we not have to keep going
down? And and I mean, obviously, that's
the question on everyone's mind. If you
look at 2018, you'll see something
similar, right? Like, we had some nice
rallies. Bitcoin rallied in a or sorry
in from June to the August high Bitcoin
rallied about or the July high we
rallied about almost 50%. And then we've
had another rally in in um August
where Bitcoin rallied about 26% up to
the bare market resistance band and then
just gave it all back. So I mean there's
a couple of things to consider. I would
argue one of the things to look at a
little bit closer is the 200 day because
we did get a daily close above that and
that is certainly something right like
that's not you can't just scoff at it
and pretend like it doesn't matter.
There are times in in history where you
get above the 200 day moving average and
it's a good sign, right? Like if you
look at what happened in 2023 and if you
look at what happened in, you know,
after the low in 2018 going into 2019,
right? getting above the 200 day moving
average was a good sign. There's also
been, you know, a couple of bare markets
where it wasn't, right? Like in 2014,
uh, where we got above the 200 day SMA a
couple of times and it didn't
necessarily mean anything. And after
getting above the 200 day moving
average, we then fell into the October
low. Um, and we've made the comparison
to 2019 a couple of times, uh, in terms
of the business cycle, and we got above
the 200 day moving average in that a
couple of times. Now, one of them was
the pandemic, but even without the
pandemic, we got above the 200 day
moving average and then still went, you
know, still went on to put in a slightly
lower low. So I think I would argue if
if this is to be sustained, then what
you would expect would be for Bitcoin to
not just simply get rejected here at the
bare market resistance band, but to
actually power through it and then to
see follow through where then you know
it holds it and then it just continues
on up.
If on the other hand, we're just
rejected here once again, then basically
we're going through the same process of
kind of just bouncing around between
these two levels until they get so close
so that the Bitcoin has to decide one
way or another. This is not the first
time, by the way, that the 20week SMA
and the 200E moving average have
converged. There's been times where they
converged like in in 2014 where you can
see that Bitcoin briefly dropped below
the 200 week. It went up to the bare
market resistance band, got rejected,
came back down, squeeze. Look at that
squeeze right there, and then eventually
it broke through and then it was a fake
out, right? And we came right back down.
2019, right? Same thing. We ended up
breaking through it. Eventually, we came
back down.
to a higher low. 2015 was a lower low.
2019 was a higher low. 2022, you can see
these two were coming together and we
just broke down below it.
So, I can't tell you which way it's
going to break. I can tell you that in
terms of time,
it's not impossible for this the bare
market to take a little bit longer. in
terms of some of the metrics like the,
you know, the MVRVZ score, it still
hasn't gone below zero and normally it
does in bare market years. If you were
to look at um the realized price, right,
historically, Bitcoin goes below the
realized price in bare markets, as you
can see, 2011, 2014, 2018, 2022. Hasn't
done it in 2026. It doesn't mean that it
has to, but it hasn't done it yet. And
so, you know, like I it's not that I
can't sympathize with why people are
getting excited right now. Like this is
one of the better moves that Bitcoin has
had in a while, right? Like we haven't
been at these prices since early June.
So, it's it's woken some people up,
right? It's certainly woken some people
up. But there's also reality too of
there have been several times that
Bitcoin has had um a little rally in
August before getting a drop a little
bit later in the year. You know, you can
see August of uh 2018 and you can see
August of 2022. Now, you might say,
"Well, hold on a second, Ben.
That's not what you said, right? What
you said was that Bitcoin would likely
go down in August. And you're right,
right? Like I did say that and and I
might be wrong about that. Right. If you
look at at midterm years, you can see
that every midterm year, Bitcoin has
gone down in August and right now it's
actually up 10%.
So what gives? Like could could Bitcoin
go down in August? I mean,
it's not as likely now as it was a week
ago, that's for sure. Because Bitcoin's
a lot higher.
But, you know, I mean, if you were to
look at 2022,
you can see that Bitcoin had a rally in
August, right? We had uh well, I guess
it was late August going into early
September, but we we had a nice little
move. We had a a rally in August in uh
in 2018, right? Look at this rally right
here that Bitcoin had in 2018 where
Bitcoin rallied up more than what it
just rallied up, right? It rallied up
almost 30%.
So, how can that be, right? How can the
month still be red when you're getting
these big rallies? Well, it's because
you get this big r a big red candle at
some point in the month. In fact, if you
look at 2022,
we zoom over to to 2022.
Bitcoin went higher in August than it
did in July. You see that candle? You
see that wick? Bitcoin went higher in
August of 2022
than it did in July 2022. But it still
closed red. Right? Right now we are
higher than we were in July. I'm not
saying it's going to close red, but
again there's some precedent for just
because you take out the monthly high
from a prior month doesn't mean that
it's over. And we actually just went
through this process in March and April,
right? Like March had a wick high, April
went a little bit higher, and then, you
know, May even went a little bit higher
and then we sold off. So,
you know, look, I'd love to get on the
bull bandwagon. I I'm looking forward
to, you know, to 2027 and hopefully just
being bullish again and and not, you
know, being on the other side of the
four-year cycle. I'd love to see that.
At the same time, there's there's still
evidence that suggests that, you know,
we could still go a little bit lower.
That doesn't mean you can't buy Bitcoin.
I think a DCA strategy makes sense, but
it just, you know, it it makes sense to
be aware of of the different pieces of
evidence out there. And if you look at
the monthly hyenashi candles, you can
see that the monthly is now slightly
green. Um,
we had one that was green back in May as
well. So, I think Bitcoin still has a
little bit to prove here. Let's see if
we can get through the uh the bare
market resistance band and if we can if
we can then hold it as support. Um, and
then we can talk, right? We can talk
about what that would mean and and how
that could could change the cycle. But
those are my thoughts for now, right? We
talked earlier about Bitcoin likely
getting back up to the bare market
resistance band at some point before the
cycle low is in. Uh well, we're there
right now. In 2018, Bitcoin was at the
bare market resistance band the week of
August 27th
and it rallied up to 7,300. And we've
talked a lot extensively about the
similarities between 20, you know, 2018
and and 2026. In fact, the low in August
um was around 5800 5,800 5900 back in uh
and here it was a little bit higher,
right? It was around yeah like 62K. But
again, like there's similarities, right?
You're you're you're finding lows around
the same time. And you can kind of
verify that by looking at the year-to-
date ROI of Bitcoin in 2026 compared to
2018. And you can see how the rallies
more or less line up. Even see this
rally lined up and then we went down,
right? We went down at the same time. We
just didn't go as far down. And then we
got we're getting another rally kind of
when we got a rally in 2018 and then
that rally lasted until early September
before it sold off. So,
we'll see. We'll see how it plays out. I
mean, certainly an interesting day in
the markets. Uh
we'll see what happens over the next few
weeks if Bitcoin can hold these levels
at the bare market resistance band or if
we just simply get rejected uh like we
have previously done this year and also
previously in midterm years. We
typically find ourselves getting
rejected by the bare market resistance
band until we get into the um the the
preh havinging year. So one week at a
time. Those are my views. Thank you guys
for tuning in. Uh if you want to go to
the ITC conference in November, make
sure you guys get your tickets. Ticket
prices are going up on September 1st.
I'll see you guys next time. Bye.